<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://mikelisterphotography.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://mikelisterphotography.co.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-02-10T21:14:50+00:00</updated><id>https://mikelisterphotography.co.uk/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Mike Lister Photography</title><subtitle>Professional photography services in Plymouth, Devon and Cornwall. Wedding, Commercial and Drone Photography.</subtitle><author><name>Mike Lister</name></author><entry><title type="html">10 Essential Wedding Photography Tips for Devon &amp;amp; Cornwall Brides</title><link href="https://mikelisterphotography.co.uk/10-Essential-Wedding-Photography-Tips" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10 Essential Wedding Photography Tips for Devon &amp;amp; Cornwall Brides" /><published>2024-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://mikelisterphotography.co.uk/wedding-tips-devon-cornwall</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mikelisterphotography.co.uk/10-Essential-Wedding-Photography-Tips"><![CDATA[<p>Your wedding day is one of the most important days of your life, and as a Devon-based photographer who’s captured countless weddings across the South West, I’ve learned what makes for truly magical wedding photos.</p>

<h2 id="1-embrace-the-golden-hour">1. Embrace the Golden Hour</h2>

<p>The South West coast offers some of the most stunning golden hour light you’ll find anywhere in the UK. For Devon and Cornwall weddings, I always recommend scheduling couple portraits during:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Summer weddings:</strong> 7-8:30 PM</li>
  <li><strong>Spring/Autumn weddings:</strong> 5-6:30 PM</li>
  <li><strong>Winter weddings:</strong> 3-4 PM</li>
</ul>

<p>This soft, warm light creates flattering portraits with that dreamy, romantic quality every couple wants.</p>

<h2 id="2-choose-locations-with-meaning">2. Choose Locations with Meaning</h2>

<p>Whether it’s the beach where you got engaged, a local park you walk through every weekend, or your favourite coastal path, choosing locations that mean something to you adds genuine emotion to your photos.</p>

<p><strong>Popular South West locations include:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Devon:</strong> Dartmoor tors, South Hams beaches, historic market towns</li>
  <li><strong>Cornwall:</strong> Coastal paths, fishing villages, subtropical gardens</li>
  <li><strong>Both:</strong> Country houses with coastal views</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="3-trust-your-photographers-timeline-advice">3. Trust Your Photographer’s Timeline Advice</h2>

<p>I’ve photographed weddings at every major venue in Devon and Cornwall, and I know exactly how long things take. When I suggest allowing extra time for travel between locations or portraits, it’s because I know:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Coastal roads can be busy in summer</li>
  <li>Weather can change quickly</li>
  <li>You’ll want to enjoy moments, not rush through them</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="4-prepare-for-all-weather">4. Prepare for All Weather</h2>

<p>The South West weather is famously changeable! Some of my favourite wedding photos have been in the rain, mist, or dramatic stormy skies. My advice:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Have clear umbrellas on standby (they make great props!)</li>
  <li>Trust that moody weather can create incredible atmosphere</li>
  <li>Embrace indoor alternatives with character</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="5-the-first-look-advantage">5. The First Look Advantage</h2>

<p>More couples are opting for a “first look” - a private moment before the ceremony where you see each other for the first time. Benefits include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>More relaxed portraits before the ceremony</li>
  <li>Extra time for creative shots</li>
  <li>A private, intimate moment just for you two</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="6-communicate-with-your-photographer">6. Communicate with Your Photographer</h2>

<p>The more I know about what’s important to you, the better I can capture it. Tell me about:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Special family dynamics</li>
  <li>Sentimental details or heirlooms</li>
  <li>Any surprises you’re planning</li>
  <li>Parts of the day you’re most excited about</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="7-dont-over-schedule-your-day">7. Don’t Over-schedule Your Day</h2>

<p>Some of the best wedding photos happen in the unplanned moments - laughter during speeches, spontaneous dancing, quiet conversations. Leave space in your timeline for:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Natural interactions with guests</li>
  <li>Breathers between events</li>
  <li>Just enjoying being married!</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="8-consider-a-second-photographer">8. Consider a Second Photographer</h2>

<p>For larger weddings or when you want comprehensive coverage, a second photographer can:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Capture getting ready from both perspectives</li>
  <li>Photograph guests during ceremony</li>
  <li>Get different angles of key moments</li>
  <li>Cover more ground at larger venues</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="9-personalise-your-details">9. Personalise Your Details</h2>

<p>Your wedding details tell your story. I love photographing:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Handwritten vows or notes</li>
  <li>Family heirlooms incorporated into outfits</li>
  <li>Local flowers and produce</li>
  <li>Personalised decor elements</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="10-enjoy-the-experience">10. Enjoy the Experience</h2>

<p>Most importantly, remember that your wedding photos should reflect a day you actually enjoyed. When you’re relaxed and having fun, it shows in every photo.</p>

<h2 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>Your Devon or Cornwall wedding has its own unique character, influenced by the stunning landscapes and coastal light. By planning thoughtfully and trusting your photographer’s experience with South West weddings, you’ll have photos that not only document your day but truly capture its spirit.</p>

<p><em>Mike Lister has been photographing weddings across Devon, Cornwall, and the South West for over 10 years. Based in Plymouth, he combines documentary storytelling with artistic portraiture to create wedding albums that families treasure for generations.</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Mike Lister</name></author><category term="Wedding" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Planning a wedding in the South West? Discover essential photography tips to make your Devon or Cornwall wedding photos truly magical.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://mikelisterphotography.co.uk/assets/images/wedding/devon-wedding-photographer-plymstock-church-ceremony.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://mikelisterphotography.co.uk/assets/images/wedding/devon-wedding-photographer-plymstock-church-ceremony.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>